englishbaby.com 2004-12-24

# English, baby! - Services for English Language Programs

| 

| **Policy overview:**|     
---|---  
Safeguarding your privacy is serious business. That's why English, baby!'s policy is simple: Except as provided in this statement, English, baby! will not disclose, sell or rent any personally identifiable information without proper consent. You, the English, baby! user, always have the final word on whether English, baby! knows who you are. It is your choice whether you wish to share personally identifiable information with English, baby!. We encourage you to consider sharing information with English, baby! only if you receive true value in exchange for that information. Please use discretion when revealing personally identifiable information while using English, baby! tools, as it may be collected and used by unauthorized third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of English, baby!. In other words, if for some reason you post your home phone number on the English, baby! message boards (which you should NOT do), you're on your own. Please take a minute to read our policy so that you understand your options and how English, baby! collects, processes and shares information. If you have any questions about English, baby!'s information practices, send an email to English, baby!'s [Policy Manager](mailto:privacy@englishbaby.com). 

The following is a summary overview of English, baby!'s privacy policy. Click on the "more" button after each section to read the complete description of English, baby!'s information collection practices.  
  
**What information does English, baby! collect?**|   
If you decide to join English, baby!, registration is the only place where you are required to submit information about yourself. To become an English, baby! member you need to submit your email address (which can be your new English, baby! email address), gender, birthdate, zip or postal code and the name of the country where you live.  
**What are cookies and how does English, baby! use them?**|   
The main function of cookies is to connect members with their stored account information so that English, baby! can deliver better and more personalized service. Cookies do not enable the English, baby! staff to access personally identifiable information that you haven't already provided.  
**How does English, baby! use member information?**|   
English, baby! uses information collected from you and other members primarily to provide more personalized service, and to learn more about its audience demographic. English, baby! also collects market research data in order to generate sales to corporate clients. Market research data are always anonymous and are never used to sell anything to individual respondents based on their personal responses.  
**What information does English, baby! log?**|   
English, baby! logs information automatically transmitted from your browser (URL of the web page you were on before coming to English, baby!, IP address and browser version); information you submit through registration, forms for optional programs, surveys and other entries; and communications transmitted through English, baby! tools.  
**What is English, baby!'s information retention policy?**|   
To preserve our database, English, baby! retains information submitted by members for an indefinite length of time. English, baby! understands your submissions as consent to store all your information in one place for this indefinite length of time. English, baby! will nullify (scramble so that it is unrecognizable) account information if required by law or in response to a written member request.  
**How does English, baby! secure collected information?**|   
English, baby! makes every effort to make sure your information is secure. Your English, baby! account is password-protected so that only you and authorized English, baby! employees can access your information.  
**With whom does English, baby! share information?**|   
When you submit information to English, baby!, it is shared only with the owners of the referring educational program web site. English, baby! reserves the right to disclose user information if required by law or if English, baby! has reason to believe that the law is being violated.  
**What is English, baby!'s opt-in/out policy?**|   
During registration you choose whether to receive correspondence from either English, baby! or its partners, and whether you want to participate in a variety of English, baby! programs. This information lives on your Profile where you can, at any point, easily edit it to indicate that you have changed your mind. As for promotions, contests, submission opportunities and programs, you will not be included unless you opt-in.  
**How can English, baby! members edit their personal information?**|   
English, baby! believes strongly in giving you the ability to access and edit your personal information. You can always update the personal information in your Profile by clicking on the "Update Profile" link on the site. You can edit your Profile or account settings at any time -- all you need is your member name and password.  
**What action has English, baby! taken to protect children's privacy?**|   
Because English, baby! is intended for people ages 15 and over, its registration policy is intentionally designed to identify people who are 14 or younger. English, baby! will not knowingly collect any information from children under 13. English, baby! has developed a process to verify and delete accounts belonging to members who are discovered to be under 13.  
Note to Parents:  
If your child is under 13 and has become an English, baby! member using a false age, please notify English, baby!'s [Policy Manager](mailto:privacy@englishbaby.com), who will immediately close the account and nullify all personally identifiable information collected from them. If your child is under the age of 18 and you would like to know more about English, baby!'s site, information practices, stored information or how to close your child's account, contact the Policy Manager.  
**Notification of Changes:**|   
English, baby!'s security and privacy policy are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary. This policy might change as English, baby! updates and expands its services. English, baby! will contact you via email and post notification if there are any material changes in its privacy practices. English, baby! also encourages you to also check the privacy policy out periodically.  
**How can I reach English, baby! staff?**|   
If you have technical problems, questions or other issues related to your use of English, baby!, please [email us](mailto:privacy@englishbaby.com). English, baby!'s Policy Manager will respond to all requests sent through mail or email from members and parents interested in knowing more about personal information stored on the English, baby! database, having their personal information nullified, or have additional questions regarding privacy.  
  
**What information does English, baby! collect?**  
English, baby! wants to be your favorite online destination. To encourage your participation, your English, baby! experience is personalized so that you are offered the services, products and information most relevant to you. This requires the collection of information to help tell you apart from other English, baby! members. The forms are specially designed so that you don't have to disclose any more information than is necessary to participate in a given activity or use a given tool. 

English, baby! collects two kinds of information: anonymous and personally identifiable. Anonymous information is not associated with specific individuals. For instance, English, baby! may know how many people read this Privacy Policy today, but they don't necessarily know their names, addresses or birthdays. Personally identifiable information reveals who you are and/or how you can be contacted. It includes your name, address, phone number and email address. 

Below is a summary of the different ways English, baby! collects various kinds of information about members: 

**Registration (mandatory to be an English, baby! member)**  
If you decide to join English, baby!, registration is the only place where you will be required to submit information about yourself. To become an English, baby! member, you need to complete a form with your email address (which can be your new English, baby! email address), gender, birthday, zip code, country (and other related information). English, baby! uses this information to provide you with more personalized service, and to learn more about its audience demographics. 

Only when you choose to participate in optional English, baby! programs or services will registration information be linked to information you submit for other purposes. For example, if you decide to be an English, baby! Rep, you'll be asked to provide English, baby! with your full name, address, school and graduating class. English, baby! keeps this information in its database with your member name and other registration data. If you decide that you no longer want English, baby! to have a certain piece of information about you, email the [Policy Manager](mailto:privacy@englishbaby.com).   
**Your Member Profile (optional)**  
Information from registration will automatically be placed in your Member Profile. In addition, you can choose to tell everyone your hobbies, interests, likes and dislikes by creating a Member Gallery (or Alumni) Profile. You can fill out as much or as little of your Profile as you want. The more you fill out, the more likely it is that you'll be able to meet members based on things you have in common.   
**Wireless (optional)**  
In your account settings, you can register to receive English, baby! text messages on your cell phone or pager. To do this, you must submit your device's area code and number as well as the confirmation number English, baby! provides to you. The wireless information you submit is linked to your member name and stored in a database that only authorized English, baby! technical staff can access. For your protection, the tech staff has devised a system of verification to ensure that nobody but you can register your device.   
**Other places (optional)**  
English, baby! runs promotions, contests, submission opportunities, surveys and programs designed to improve your experience on English, baby!. To participate in these programs you may have to give contact (name, address, email address) and/or demographic (i.e., age, gender) information. This only goes to the authorized English, baby! employees who run the promotion, contest or program so that they can inform you if you win, ask you questions about your submission and deal with other relevant details. English, baby! understands your decision to participate as permission to contact you, if necessary, and to store this additional information in its databases with your registration data.   
**Public forums (privacy warning)**  
English, baby! understands your decision to post in public areas as permission to contact you through your English, baby! account. 

One last thing to keep in mind: Whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information on message boards, through email, English, baby! Member Galleries, Alumni Spotlights, Message Boards, or in chat, it can be collected and used by anyone, including law-enforcement agencies acting under subpoena power. If you post personal information in public places, others may send you unsolicited email messages. Always be smart about the information you provide online. And, be aware that if English, baby! employees find personally identifiable information posted in public areas, they will delete it. 

back to top

**What are cookies, and how does English, baby! use them?**  
English, baby! collects anonymous information through cookies. A cookie is a small piece of data containing a unique identification number that is sent to your browser from a web server, and is stored on your computer's hard drive. The unique ID number identifies your browser to English, baby!'s computers whenever you visit. Cookies do not enable anyone to access personally identifiable information that you have not already given us. English, baby! primarily uses cookies to connect members with account information stored on English, baby!'s computers. This helps English, baby! deliver better and more personalized service. English, baby! also uses cookies to estimate English, baby!'s audience size for advertisers; to track the number of entries in English, baby! promotions, sweepstakes and contests; to identify the areas of the site you visit; to hold session information; and to track user preferences. 

Cookies are part of the technology implemented by your browser. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to either notify you when you have received a cookie, or to refuse them all together. To find out more about cookies on Netscape, [click here](http://home.netscape.com/privacy/index.html). For information about cookies on Microsoft Internet Explorer, [click here](http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.htm). 

English, baby! uses both permanent and temporary cookies. Permanent cookies stay with your browser, whereas temporary cookies go away after you close your browser. English, baby! uses permanent cookies in order to recognize you between visits. English, baby! uses temporary cookies to store information about your current visit to the site. That information goes away when you close your browser or shut down your computer. If you choose to not accept cookies, you cannot participate as a registered, signed-in member. 

back to top

**How does English, baby! use member information?**  
English, baby!'s decisions regarding the use of information collected from English, baby! members are based on two areas of interest: market research, and improving user experience by offering personalized service and content. 

English, baby! may analyze information provided directly by you, or obtained through cookies or third parties to direct services and content based on your interests. This is done in the aggregate (for example, let's say half of English, baby!'s members are females who visit the boards more than the chat rooms) and at the individual level (for example, English, baby! User1234 mostly visits the Eavesdropping Lesson). Again, this helps the staff produce and appropriately feature tools and content tailored to your interests. 

English, baby! collects market research data in order to generate sales to corporate clients. Market research data are always anonymous and are never used to sell anything to individual respondents based on their personal responses. Market research data, however, may be used at the aggregate level to:   
1\. Increase the likelihood that a group's experience on English, baby! is relevant to its interests as a whole  
2\. Formulate group-level statistical models that are used to accomplish goal #1 (above). 

English, baby!'s market research data is collected in two ways:   
1\. Among individuals who opt-in to take surveys during the registration process or while on English, baby! (those who sign up are contacted and take surveys through email).  
2\. Through surveys that we publicly post on English, baby! (it is never mandatory to answer these surveys). 

English, baby! uses data at the individual level to sell products and services to English, baby! members who express an interest in these products and services, through a poll for example, or to members who can be presumed to have an interest based on results from a statistical analysis. 

back to top

**What information does English, baby! log?**  
When you surf the Internet, your browser automatically transmits information to the web sites you visit, including English, baby!. Such information includes referral data (URL of the web page you were on before coming to English, baby!), IP address and your browser version. English, baby! collects this information to help improve services and moderate the site. All the information that is automatically submitted by your browser is considered anonymous. 

English, baby! also logs information you submit through registration, forms for optional programs, surveys and other entries, cookie data and communications transmitted through English, baby! applications. Only authorized English, baby! staff have access to your information in its entirety. Other employees may have access to bits and pieces of this information if it pertains to their job duties. 

**What is English, baby!'s information retention policy?**  
To preserve the integrity of our databases, standard procedure calls for us to retain information submitted by members for an indefinite length of time. English, baby! understands your submissions as consent to store all your information in one place for this indefinite length of time, if we so wish. If required by law, as is the case to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we will nullify (scramble so that it is unrecognizable) member information. We will also respond to written member requests to nullify account information. If you wish to make such a request, which requires that we verify your identity, or if you have any questions regarding this policy, contact English, baby!'s [Policy Manager](mailto:privacy@englishbaby.com). 

back to top

**How does English, baby! secure collected information?**  
Your English, baby! Profile is password-protected so that only you and authorized English, baby! employees have access to your account information. In order to maintain this protection, do not give your password to anyone. If anyone ever asks you for information claiming they are English, baby! staff, check their Member Profile -- if it doesn't say they are staff, they're not. Also, if you share a computer, you should sign out of your English, baby! account and close the browser window before someone else logs on. This will protect your information on public terminals. 

English, baby! makes every effort to ensure that your information is secure on its system. Only certain authorized English, baby! employees can access this information if it's relevant to their job duties. English, baby! has staff dedicated to maintaining this Privacy Policy and other privacy initiatives, periodically reviewing web security and making sure that every English, baby! employee is aware of our security practices. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed 100% secure. As a result, English, baby! cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. 

**With whom does English, baby! share information?**  
When you submit information to English, baby!, it is generally collected, processed and maintained solely by us. Sometimes we may allow partner companies to collect information about members from us or directly from you via their web site. When English, baby! is the source, it is usually so that we can provide a service with a partner. We choose to work with upstanding companies that will treat your information responsibly. But, since we don't own these companies, we can't speak for them on privacy issues. Before telling them about yourself, check out their privacy statements. If you are not satisfied with their information practices, you can choose to not use their service. 

Below is a summary of the situations in which English, baby! might share information: 

**Co-Branding**  
Some of our services, such as English, baby! email, are offered in conjunction with partner companies. In order to provide these services, English, baby! may choose to share some of you user data (e.g., user name and email address).   
**Content Partners**  
Some English, baby! content is “sponsored by” or “presented by” other companies. English, baby! typically shares market research data (how the sponsorship performed, names of contest winners, etc.) collected on the site or via email surveys with these partners. This information is aggregate and not linked to specific users.   
**Partner Sponsorships**  
Partners may sponsor promotions, contests and sweepstakes that require you to reveal details such as your name, address or phone number. Always check their privacy policy before revealing information about yourself. If you don't want these sponsors to have your personal information, you can choose to not participate. 

When visitors come to English, baby!, they may receive cookies from English, baby!'s sponsors; this information is not shared with English, baby!. This privacy statement does not address the information practices of our advertisers. You should read the privacy statements of all third-party sites, as their privacy policies may differ from English, baby!'s. 

Finally, English, baby! reserves the right to disclose user information from both private and public areas of the site if required by law or if given reason to believe, in our sole discretion, that someone is causing injury to or interference with the rights of English, baby! members or the general public, or with English, baby!'s rights of property. 

back to top

**What is English, baby!'s opt-in/out policy?**  
During registration you choose whether to receive correspondence from either English, baby! or its partners and whether you want to participate in a variety of English, baby! programs. This information lives on your Profile where you can, at any point, easily edit it to indicate that you have changed your mind. As for promotions, contests, submission opportunities and programs, you will not be included unless you opt-in. 

If you receive unsolicited email from an English, baby! domain, please contact English, baby!'s [Policy Manager](mailto:privacy@englishbaby.com). 

**How can English, baby! members edit their information?**  
English, baby! believes strongly in giving you the ability to access and edit your personal information. 

You can always update the personal information in your Profile by clicking on the "Update Profile" link on the site. You can edit your Profile or account settings at any time -- all you need is your member name and password. 

So that we can protect the integrity of sensitive data, there are certain pieces of information, such as your birthday, that you cannot alter yourself. For example, since children under 15 are not allowed to register as English, baby! members, we need to take reasonable measures to preserve the accuracy of our members' ages. 

Our databases automatically update any personal information you edit in your Profile, or that you request we edit. Information transmitted through message boards, MyNotes, MyVocab, polls, and chat remain in our databases. Keep this in mind if you decide to communicate personal information through any of these applications. 

back to top

 **What action has English, baby! taken to protect children's privacy?**  
English, baby! is intended for people 15 or over. Our registration process is intentionally designed to identify children under 15 years of age. We have also made an effort to specifically limit English, baby!'s appeal to people of age 15 and older. English, baby! will not knowingly collect any information from children under 13. If it comes to our attention that a member has revealed on English, baby! that they are under 13, a member of English, baby!'s Community staff will immediately delete the account. 

**Note to parents:**  
If your child is under 13 and has become an English, baby! member using a false age, please notify the 

[Policy Manager](mailto:privacy@englishbaby.com) who will immediately close the account and nullify all personally identifiable information collected from them. If your child is under the age of 18 and you would like to know more about our site, information practices, stored information on your child, or how to close your child's account, contact English, baby!'s Policy Manager.   
back to top

 **Notification of Changes:**  
English, baby!'s security and privacy policy are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary. This policy might change as English, baby! updates and expands its services. English, baby! will contact you via email and post notification if there are any material changes in its privacy practices. English, baby! also encourages you to also check the privacy policy out periodically. 

**How can I reach English, baby! staff?**  
If you have technical problems, questions or other issues related to your use of English, baby!, please email [help@englishbaby.com](mailto:help@englishbaby.com). 

English, baby!'s 

[Policy Manager](mailto:privacy@englishbaby.com) will respond to all requests sent through mail or email from members and parents interested in knowing more about what personal information is stored on the English, baby! database, or if they want their personal information nullified, or have additional questions regarding privacy. 

English, baby! Inc.   
back to top
